sofarsounds.com 2013-12-30

# Sofar Sounds • Sofar Sounds Privacy Policy

## Introduction

The website [](http://www.sofarsounds.com/)[www.sofarsounds.com](http://www.sofarsounds.com/) is owned and operated by Sofar Sounds Ltd (“Sofar”, “we”, “our”, “us”).  We are committed to respecting and protecting your privacy and any data that we collect concerning you.  This policy (“Privacy Policy”) sets out the basis on which we collect personal data from you, or that you provide to us.  

Sofar is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected.  Any information you provide to us by which you may be identified when using the Website will only be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully in order to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data.  

By using the Website or the Sofar services you agree to the use of the data that we collect in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  We collect the minimum amount of information about you that is commensurate with providing you with a satisfactory service.

### Information Collected

In order to use certain features of the Website, you will need to register.  We may collect and process the following information about you:

a) User Registration: personal information that you provide when registering as a user on the Website including but not limited to your name or Facebook username, date of birth and email address.

b) Facebook  Registration: by registering your Sofar account through your account with Facebook you will allow Sofar access to your basic information stored with Facebook, including your name, gender, networks, user ID, list of friends, and any other information that you have made public.

c) Site Visits: details of any visits you make to the Website which may include, but is not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs, other communication data, and the resources that you access or use.

d) IP Address and browser information: we may collect information about your computer, laptop or mobile media device which may include, but is not limited to, your IP address, operating system and browser type.  Such information helps us to develop the Website.

e) Cookies: for the same reason, we may also obtain information about your general Internet usage and browsing habits.  We may do this by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer.  Please read section below for more information on cookies.

f) Events: we may request additional information if you register for an event.  Such additional information may include your name, age, gender and other demographic information.

g) Hosts: we may request additional information if you register to become a host.  Such additional information may include your name, address, age, gender and other demographic information.

h) Artists: we may request additional information if you register to play at Sofar.  Such additional information include your name, age gender and other demographic information.

i) Records: if you contact us to report an abuse, make a complaint, report a problem with the Website or for any other reason, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

j) Surveys: we may provide you with with opportunity to complete surveys that we may use for research purposes.  These surveys are optional and you may decide not to respond to them.

## Consent and Storage

a) By disclosing any information to Sofar through the Website and by using the Website as a registered user, you are consenting to the collection, storage and use of your personal information by Sofar as set out in this Privacy Policy and our Terms.  You understand and grant consent to the collection, maintenance, processing and transfer of such information in and to the European Economic Area (“EAA”) and other countries and territories.  If you do not consent to the collection, maintenance, processing and transfer of such information to territories in and to the EEA and other countries and territories, then you should not use the Website as a registered user, which means that many features of the Website will be unavailable to you.

b) When you give your personally identifiable information to Sofar, it may be used by Sofar and its direct and indirect consolidated subsidiaries for the purposes of, for example but not limited to, providing you services and sending you correspondence, and additionally may be transferred to entities other than Sofar’s affiliates, which entities may be located in countries outside the EEA, including the United States.  Each of these countries has different privacy laws that afford varying levels of protection for your personally identifiable information, and such laws may not be as comprehensive as those that exist in the EEA.  By registering with Sofar, you consent to Sofar’s and its direct and indirect consolidated subsidiaries’ transmission to, and processing of your information in any jurisdiction, in accordance with its Privacy Policy.  We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

c) The transmission of information via the Internet is never completely secure.  Although Sofar will do its best to protect your personal data and use industry standard procedures and security features to try t prevent any unauthorised access by a third party, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Website.  You accept that transmission of your personal data is done at your own risk.

## Information Use

a) We will use the email address provided by you when you register to contact you from time to time.  This may be for security reasons (so that we can check that you are who you say you are), to ask your opinion about the Website, or it may be to keep you updated on the services currently available on the Website and any changes to those services and those that we intend to launch in the future.

b) We may also use such personal information to send you notices, on behalf of others and ourselves, regarding products and services that we thank may be of interest to you.

c) Non-personally identifiable information may be shared with third parties to help us to introduce, develop and improve the Website, Sofar’s services or for other purposes.

d) We may use your email address to contact you and send you notifications or information related to the Website or to Sofar’s services.  We may also use your email address for security reasons so that we can verify your identity.

e) We believe in privacy and therefore will take all reasonable measures to ensure that your personally identifiable information remains private.  However, in the event that we are required to disclose personally identifiable information by a court, the police or other law enforcement bodies for their investigations, regulation or other governmental authority we will make such a disclosure without being in violation of this Privacy Policy.

## Acquisition and Disposals

If Sofar is acquired by another company or sells all or a portion of its assets to another company, or in the event of a merger, it is likely that user information will be a part of the assets transferred.  If as a result of such a business transition information is to be collected, used or disclosed in a manner or for a purpose different from that stated above, Sofar will endeavour to notify all users of such changes beforehand.

## Links

The Website may contain links to and from Third Party Sites.  If you follow a link to any Third Party Site, please note that these website have their own privacy policies.  We do not accept any responsibility or liability for such policies.  You should check these policies before you submit any personal data to such Third Party Sites.

## Children

If you are under the age of 12, you must ask permission of you parent or guardian before you register.  We do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone who is under the age of 12 or allow them to register as a user of the Website.  If it comes to our attention that we have collected personal information from such a person then we will delete this information including as quickly as possible.  If you have reason to believe that this has occurred then please contact us at info@sofarsounds.com and we will delete all relevant personal information.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small file that contains information that is transferred to your computer, laptop or mobile media device’s hard drive.  Once the file is added the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site.  Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual.  The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use cookies to identify you as a valid user and to help personalise your Sofar experience in conjunction with your profile.  Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which page you find useful and which you do not.  A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.  We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information provided by users.  

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the settings on your browser which allows you to refuse the settings of cookies.  You can learn how to do this by accessing the “Help” function on your browser.  However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain part of the Website or discover that you have reduced functionality whilst using the Website.  Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that is will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to the Website.

## Changes to this Policy

We may, at our sole discretion, amend, modify or change this Privacy Policy.  Al such changes will be placed on this page and will supersede this version of our Privacy Policy.  You should check this page from time to time to ensure that it still meets with your approval.

## Data Protection

Sofar complies with the The Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), including UK amending legislation and E.U. Directives.  The Act gives you the right to access information held about you.  If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, or if you want to know what information we have collected about you, please contact us.  You can also correct any factual errors in that information or require us to remove your details from any list under our control.
